Francis George Hall Letters
Francis George Hall Letters
1892-1901
Hall, Francis George.
0.5 linear feet
Correspondence of a colonial administrator in Kenya, written to his father, Lieutenant Colonel Edward Hall.
149029
Biographical History
Francis George Hall (1860-1901) was a British Colonial administrator in Kenya. He worked for the Bank of England until 1880 then, in South Africa, as a schoolteacher, soldier, farmer, and gold miner. In 1892 he joined the Imperial British East Africa Company and became Acting Superintendent of the District of Kikuyu. Hall remained as District Officer after company control was ceded to the British government.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Francis George Hall Letters consists of typescript copies of letters from Hall to his father, Lieutenant-Colonel Edward Hall, and an index to the letters. The collection also includes a second photocopied set of the letters and indexes.
Arrangement of the Collection
Letters are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
London University's Department of Oriental and African Studies has another collection of Hall's letters.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Hall, E., fl 1860-1901, Lieutenant Colonel.; Hall, Francis George, 1860-1901.; Great Britain -- Colonies -- Africa -- Administration.; Decolonization -- Africa -- History.; Africa -- Politics and government -- To 1945.; Kikuyu (Kenya) -- Politics and government -- 19th century.; Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence, typescript
  - Pages 1-211, 1892-1895; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Appendix with notes, pp. 212-217, 1893; undated (Box 1)
  - Pages 1-131, 1896-1901; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Appendix with notes, pp. 132-162, 1893; undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence, photocopies
  - Pages 1-211, 1892-1895; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Appendix with notes, pp. 212-217, 1893; undated (Box 1)
  - Pages 1-131, 1896-1901; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Appendix with notes, pp. 132-162, 1893; undated (Box 1)